Asha Maurya Edison, NJ | Cell (770) 500-9413 | <u>a.maurya@att.net</u> LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Software development professional with demonstrated experience in analysis, forecasting, and modeling including leading transformative projects including process optimization, software implementation, and strategic organizational realignment. Adept communicator with the ability to work effectively in multifunctional teams.

SKILLS

Python, Django, GitHub (version control, Projects, Issues), Bootstrap4/5, Data Analytics, currently learning Swift and JavaScript, Data Structures, Algorithms

WEB APPS

Mental Health Advocacy Demo Code	Python/Django/JavaScript/SQLite/HTML/CSS/Bootstrap - A mental health and wellness awareness resource that introduces users to the adverse childhood experience (ACE) breakdown and a quiz to calculate their score. A search bar logic is available to user, a query to the resources table and if the query matches the zip code, HiddenInput widget is used so multiple forms on one template for the reviews/comments page.
House Plant Raspberry Pi Demo Code	Python/Django/Bootstrap/SQLite/ HTML/CSS/JS/Raspberry Pi - The HousePlant app reminds the user when to water plants, as well as record fertilization, repotting, etc. I used signal processing and set handlers for asynchronous events and random. User authentication displays plant catalog per user, watering delay is highlighted on card, water all plants. Edge computing is used with a Raspberry pi soil moisture meter and light sensor. Unit tests are utilized to ensure user profiles, plant set up, user authentication and rendering work correctly.
Color Game tkinker GUI Code	Python/tKinker/GUI - The Color Game uses the tkinter module and the random module, the label and entry widgets and layout managers. Build a GUI Color Game with a twist, where you have to type the name of the color of the text displayed on screen as opposed to the color names.

EXPERIENCE

Underdog Devs New York, NY

Software Engineer Apprentice

Current

• As a full-time paid apprentice in an intensive software engineering preparatory program. I gain valuable experience through daily pair programming with senior software engineers and weekly interview style algorithm programming challenges.

Columbia University New York, NY

Justice Through Code Program - Teaching Assistant

Current

- Provide a critical support role in teaching the virtual full stack web development intensive 28-week program.
- Support synchronous sessions as well as asynchronous support to the cohort to ensure the student comprehension and learning.
- Provide office hours and ad-hoc tutoring as their cohort work toward completion of the program.
 - o Python Fundamentals, Object-oriented programming (OOP) & Django framework
 - o Git/GitHub version control, projects and issues
 - Debugging
 - O Data structures, Algorithms, & BigO(n)
 - API integration
 - o Static Websites (Hexo)

Independent Contractor

Atlanta, GA

Asha Maurya Edison, NJ | Cell (770) 500-9413 | <u>a.maurya@att.net</u> LinkedIn | GitHub

Business Development, Client Relations, HR

2014 to Current

- Charted data series, scatter plot charts and financial reports to demonstrate cause and effects using collected and digitized data.
- Directed large-scale rearrangement of large box store including explaining CAD drawings, Plan-o-grams and visual merchandising technical instructions.
- While strategizing for Series A capital raising, carried out data migration to SalesForce and managed HR/Finance departments.

ShiftGig Atlanta, GA

National on-demand staffing agency and technology company

Recruiting Administrative Assistant & Client / Employee Liaison

2017 to 2019

- Hired over 1,500 individuals with time-to-fill below industry standards. Utilized Applicant Tracking Systems (ATS) to complete on-boarding process for candidates including executing client specific on-boarding compliance fulfillment for Coca-Cola, Amazon and DHL.
- Identified and developed strategic growth opportunities, signed 6 new clients resulting in \$500k+ in gross revenue.

Land Castle Title Atlanta, GA

Law firm with total managed revenue of \$150M+, 60 offices, 900+ employees

CFO 2009 to 2014

- Emphasized data was the main ingredient of business intelligence, a decision support tool. Thoroughly understood and analyzed data form the basis for making critical decisions based on market perceptions, customer sentiments and long-term trends. Responsible for all financial actions including tracking cash flow, analyzing to propose corrective action plans when necessary and preparing accurate forecasts.
- Supervised application design and architecture components for upgrade of Microsoft Dynamics and SQL, cloud migration and integration of payroll to ensure scalability as required, created 19% staff efficiency.
- Pioneered procedure optimization to manage 200+ account reconciliation, 500K/year wire transfers and 6M associated transactions plus exception handling.

Finance and HR Management

1995 to 2009

EDUCATION

Columbia University

New York, NY

• Justice Through Code Program

Coursera

- Data Collection and Processing with Python
- Python Data Structures
- Data Structures
- Python Functions, Files, and Dictionaries
- Python Project: pillow, tesseract, and OpenCV
- Python 3 Programming
- Python Basics
- Programming for Everybody